## Bharti Patel

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

#### CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- Fremont, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

#### **TOOLS**

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch 3 InVision Axure MS Office HTML CSS Oracle Webcenter Axure RP 8

#### **SKILLS**

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Service design
Visual design

## EDUCATION

#### **General Assembly**

San Francisco, CA User Experience Design Immersive program crafted by top practitioners in the field -10 weeks Full time

**Diploma in Commercial Arts** Nirmala Niketan, India

## CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design Santa Clara, CA Learn IT - Computer Graphics San Mateo, CA

#### PROFILE

I'm a Designer with a passion for creativity. I believe that simplicity is the ultimate sophistication – that less is more. I have an extensive background in graphic design, web design, and advertising. I bring my experience, passion, and professionalism to any creative task.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## UX/UI Designer - 12 Digit Marketing Jun 2017-Oct 2017

- Working with team to improve UI and providing right solution to the interface and, delivering pixel perfect mockups for development.
- Producing mock ups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product
- Working with Client Service Manager with visual designs for Retail/Brand creative campaigns delivering responsive designs.

## UX Designer & Visual Designer- Cisco Systems Jan 2017-May 2017

- Worked as one of the UX designer & Visual Designer for Cisco VTS (Virtual Topology Systems) product.
- Collaborated with service provider customers like Version and Turk Cell.
- Worked on the Visuals for VTS poster using the personas.
- Produced mock ups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.

\*\*\* Was preparing for her UX design course during this period Jan 2016 - Mar 2016 \*\*\*

## UX Designer - Incorta April 2016-May 2016

- 3-weeks worked with Incorta that provides same-day analytics for business user & allows business to use data more quickly.
- Worked on the catalog section that needed clear and engaging interface.
- Provided solution by creating more user friendly, welcoming layout.
- User & stakeholder interviews, surveys, contextual inquiry, competitive and comparative analysis, and usability testing drove the design of the prototype.

## UX Designer - San Francisco Bicycle Coalition (SFBC) March 2016-April 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an mobile app that allows SFBC members to communicate and share with each other.
- User interviews, survey, competitive & comparative analysis, user flow, site maps,
- concept model, and wireframes. Usability testing drove the design of the prototype.

## Bharti Patel

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

#### CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- Fremont, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

#### TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch 3 InVision Axure MS Office HTML CSS Oracle Webcenter Axure RP 8

#### **SKILLS**

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Service design
Visual design

### **EDUCATION**

#### **General Assembly**

San Francisco, CA
User Experience Design
Immersive program crafted
by top practitioners in the field
-10 weeks Full time

**Diploma in Commercial Arts** Nirmala Niketan, India

#### CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design Santa Clara, CA Learn IT - Computer Graphics San Mateo, CA

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# UX Designer - Progress Hardware -Ecommerce website March 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an ecommerce website that helps to find right tool
  for loyal customers who don't like to go to stores, through detailed reviews,
  update inventory & same day shipping option.
- Used stakeholder interviews, competitive and comparative analysis, card sorting, and usability testing to inform design of global navigation as well as search and check out flows.

## Web / Visual Designer- Ross Stores Inc. Dublin, CA Oct 2013- Dec 2015

- Researched & redesigned intranet portal using Adobe Creative suite & Oracle Webcenter.
- Created meaningful and compelling designs to help users become more productive and frequently visit the portal.
- Worked on design to be simpler and user friendly from complex and abstract material.
- Collaborated extensively across department & with various stakeholders.

\*\*Freelance Projects\*\*

## Web Designer - Drishticon, Fremont, CA Dec 2014 - Mar 2015

- Worked with owner & developers to improve the UI & Visuals of their current website.
- Recreated the current logo & the banners using Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop.

## Graphic/ Web Designer - Infinilytics Inc, Santa Clara, CA May 2013 - Jul 2013

- Designed marketing and promotional materials across email, mobile, web, print, and social media.
- Created branding materials logo creation and reconstruction.
- Assisted others with layout and design worked with marketing department to improve the final product.

## Project Manager - United Way SML, Fremont, CA Mar 2009 - May 2009

- Worked as a project manager for redesigning the website for United Way Sonoma Mendocino Lake.
- Responsible for total needs of the client including management of technical and creative resource to deliver complete corporate- quality branding and web solutions.

## Web Designer - Ondemandtek, Fremont, CA Jan 2009 - Mar 2009

- Worked with various design tools including Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, and Flash to implement web designs and functionality
- Created Logo using Adobe illustrator.